# **Michael Pintar**

After spending ten years working in media, I've returned to an early creative interest in software development, and I'm very excited to bring my passion for innovation, gift for problem solving and advanced communication skills to the tech industry.

1130 S Michigan Ave Apt 1813 Chicago, IL 60605 (617) 519-9780 thepintar@gmail.com

#### **PROJECTS**

# **Get Together** — *gogettogether.herokuapp.com*

This final project at Dev Bootcamp represents the culmination of my learning and my expertise at designing and executing a complex web app. As part of a small team, I constructed the Rails back end and created database associations for storing and accessing data, assisted in coding necessary RESTful routes, coded front end jQuery for an auto-complete feature as well as a great deal of the HTML and CSS and incorporated a facebook login feature. In brief, our site allows users to register through facebook, create a local event and see other events in their area which pop up on a google map.

#### **EDUCATION**

# **Dev Bootcamp, Chicago** — 18 Week Program Graduate

2015 - 2016

Took a deep dive into learning Ruby, Rails, HTML5/CSS3, TDD, Javascript (JQuery, AJAX), Git, Heroku, and Agile Development.

# Emerson College, Boston, MA — BA Visual and Media Arts

2003 - 2006

### **EXPERIENCE**

# **The Talk Market,** New York, NY — Video Editor and Shooter

AUG 2014 - JUN 2015

Shot and edited tutorials for instructing the use of the iOS App Videolicious.

# **CML Media,** Los Angeles / New York — *Lead Editor*

JUL 2007 - OCT 2014

Shot and Edited material for web startup inthemo.com and various clients.

Innovated style and concepts for both site and client videos.

Moved cross-country to open a new office and lead small team to create content.

Travelled world-wide, leading teams to execute shoots.

#### **SKILLS**

HTML5, CSS3, SQL, Javascript (jQuery, Ajax), MVC Architecture, TDD, Agile Workflow, Ruby, Rails, Sinatra, Git, Heroku

#### **REFERENCES**

# **Matt Singer**

CEO The Talk Market matt@videolicious.com

#### Joshua Winkler

Former Director of Media, CML Media jwink2000@gmail.com